karatbars.com 2018-12-29

# Gold - Karatbars International

## **Privacy Policy:**

### **1\. An overview of data protection**

**General**  
The following gives a simple overview of what happens to your personal information when you visit our  
website. Personal information is any data with which you could be personally identified. Detailed  
information on the subject of data protection can be found in our privacy policy found below.

**Data collection on our website**

Who is responsible for the data collection on this website?  
The data collected on this website are processed by the website operator. The operator's contact details  
can be found in the website's required legal notice.

**How do we collect your data?**  
Some data are collected when you provide it to us. This could, for example, be data you enter on a  
contact form.  
Other data are collected automatically by our IT systems when you visit the website. These data are  
primarily technical data such as the browser and operating system you are using or when you accessed  
the page. These data are collected automatically as soon as you enter our website.

**What do we use your data for?**  
Part of the data is collected to ensure the proper functioning of the website. Other data can be used to  
analyze how visitors use the site.

**What rights do you have regarding your data?**  
You always have the right to request information about your stored data, its origin, its recipients, and the  
purpose of its collection at no charge. You also have the right to request that it be corrected, blocked, or  
deleted. You can contact us at any time using the address given in the legal notice if you have further  
questions about the issue of privacy and data protection. You may also, of course, file a complaint with  
the competent regulatory authorities.

**Analytics and third-party tools**  
When visiting our website, statistical analyses may be made of your surfing behavior. This happens  
primarily using cookies and analytics. The analysis of your surfing behavior is usually anonymous, i.e. we  
will not be able to identify you from this data. You can object to this analysis or prevent it by not using  
certain tools. Detailed information can be found in the following privacy policy.  
You can object to this analysis. We will inform you below about how to exercise your options in this regard.

###   
**2\. General information and mandatory information**

**Data protection**  
The operators of this website take the protection of your personal data very seriously. We treat your  
personal data as confidential and in accordance with the statutory data protection regulations and this  
privacy policy.

If you use this website, various pieces of personal data will be collected. Personal information is any data  
with which you could be personally identified. This privacy policy explains what information we collect and  
what we use it for. It also explains how and for what purpose this happens.

Please note that data transmitted via the internet (e.g. via email communication) may be subject to  
security breaches. Complete protection of your data from third-party access is not possible.

**Notice concerning the party responsible for this website**

The party responsible for processing data on this website is:

Karatbars International GmbH  
Vaihinger Straße 149A  
70567 Stuttgart  
Deutschland  
Telephone: +49 (0) 711 128 970 00  
Email: support@karatbars.com

The responsible party is the natural or legal person who alone or jointly with others decides on the  
purposes and means of processing personal data (names, email addresses, etc.).

**Revocation of your consent to the processing of your data**  
Many data processing operations are only possible with your express consent. You may revoke your  
consent at any time with future effect. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data  
processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

**Right to file complaints with regulatory authorities**  
If there has been a breach of data protection legislation, the person affected may file a complaint with the  
competent regulatory authorities. The competent regulatory authority for matters related to data protection  
legislation is the data protection officer of the German state in which our company is headquartered.

A list of data protection officers and their contact details can be found at the following link:  
[https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_linksnode. html](https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html)

**Right to data portability**  
You have the right to have data which we process based on your consent or in fulfillment of a contract  
automatically delivered to yourself or to a third party in a standard, machine-readable format. If you  
require the direct transfer of data to another responsible party, this will only be done to the extent  
technically feasible.

**SSL or TLS encryption**  
This site uses SSL or TLS encryption for security reasons and for the protection of the transmission of  
confidential content, such as the inquiries you send to us as the site operator. You can recognize an  
encrypted connection in your browser's address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and the  
lock icon is displayed in your browser's address bar.

If SSL or TLS encryption is activated, the data you transfer to us cannot be read by third parties.

**Encrypted payments on this website**  
If you enter into a contract which requires you to send us your payment information (e.g. account number  
for direct debits), we will require this data to process your payment.

Payment transactions using common means of payment (Visa/MasterCard, direct debit) are only made via  
encrypted SSL or TLS connections. You can recognize an encrypted connection in your browser's  
address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and the lock icon in your browser line is visible.

In the case of encrypted communication, any payment details you submit to us cannot be read by third  
parties.

**Opposition to promotional emails**  
We hereby expressly prohibit the use of contact data published in the context of website legal notice  
requirements with regard to sending promotional and informational materials not expressly requested. The  
website operator reserves the right to take specific legal action if unsolicited advertising material, such as  
email spam, is received.

###   
**3\. Data protection officer**

**Statutory data protection officer**  
We have appointed a data protection officer for our company.

Günter Harke  
Riensberger Str. 40B  
28359 Bremen  
Telephone: +49 (0) 163 8600740  
Email: datenschutz@karatbars.de

###   
**4\. Data collection on our website**

**Cookies**  
Some of our web pages use cookies. Cookies do not harm your computer and do not contain any viruses.  
Cookies help make our website more user-friendly, efficient, and secure. Cookies are small text files that  
are stored on your computer and saved by your browser.

Most of the cookies we use are so-called "session cookies." They are automatically deleted after your  
visit. Other cookies remain in your device's memory until you delete them. These cookies make it possible  
to recognize your browser when you next visit the site.

You can configure your browser to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a caseby-  
case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, your browser can be configured to  
automatically accept cookies under certain conditions or to always reject them, or to automatically delete  
cookies when closing your browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website.

Cookies which are necessary to allow electronic communications or to provide certain functions you wish  
to use (such as the shopping cart) are stored pursuant to Art. 6 paragraph 1, letter f of DSGVO. The  
website operator has a legitimate interest in the storage of cookies to ensure an optimized service  
provided free of technical errors. If other cookies (such as those used to analyze your surfing behavior)  
are also stored, they will be treated separately in this privacy policy.

**Server log files**  
The website provider automatically collects and stores information that your browser automatically  
transmits to us in "server log files". These are:

Browser type and browser version  
Operating system used  
Referrer URL  
Host name of the accessing computer  
Time of the server request  
IP address

These data will not be combined with data from other sources.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a  
contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

**Registration on this website**  
You can register on our website in order to access additional functions offered here. The input data will  
only be used for the purpose of using the respective site or service for which you have registered. The  
mandatory information requested during registration must be provided in full. Otherwise, we will reject  
your registration.  
To inform you about important changes such as those within the scope of our site or technical changes,  
we will use the email address specified during registration.

We will process the data provided during registration only based on your consent per Art. 6 (1)(a)  
DSGVO. You may revoke your consent at any time with future effect. An informal email making this  
request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.  
We will continue to store the data collected during registration for as long as you remain registered on our  
website. Statutory retention periods remain unaffected.

**Processing of data (customer and contract data)**  
We collect, process, and use personal data only insofar as it is necessary to establish, or modify legal  
relationships with us (master data). This is done based on Art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO, which allows the  
processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract. We collect, process and  
use your personal data when accessing our website (usage data) only to the extent required to enable  
you to access our service or to bill you for the same.

Collected customer data shall be deleted after completion of the order or termination of the business  
relationship. Legal retention periods remain unaffected.

**Data transmitted when entering into a contract with online shops, retailers, and mail order**  
We transmit personally identifiable data to third parties only to the extent required to fulfill the terms of  
your contract, for example, to companies entrusted to deliver goods to your location or banks entrusted to  
process your payments. Your data will not be transmitted for any other purpose unless you have given  
your express permission to do so. Your data will not be disclosed to third parties for advertising purposes  
without your express consent.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a  
contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

###   
**5\. Analytics and advertising**

**Google Analytics**  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service. It is operated by Google Inc., 1600  
Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies". These are text files that are stored on your computer and that  
allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your  
use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

Google Analytics cookies are stored based on Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate  
interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

**IP anonymization**  
We have activated the IP anonymization feature on this website. Your IP address will be shortened by  
Google within the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area  
prior to transmission to the United States. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address sent to a Google  
server in the US and shortened there.

Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website,

to compile reports on website activity, and to provide other services regarding website activity and Internet usage

for the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be

merged with any other data held by Google.

**Browser plugin**  
You can prevent these cookies being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser.  
However, we wish to point out that doing so may mean you will not be able to enjoy the full functionality of  
this website. You can also prevent the data generated by cookies about your use of the website (incl. your  
IP address) from being passed to Google, and the processing of these data by Google, by downloading  
and installing the browser plugin available at the following link:  
<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

**Objecting to the collection of data**  
You can prevent the collection of your data by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An optout  
cookie will be set to prevent your data from being collected on future visits to this site: Disable Google Analytics.

For more information about how Google Analytics handles user data, see Google's privacy policy:  
<https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>

**Outsourced data processing**  
We have entered into an agreement with Google for the outsourcing of our data processing and fully  
implement the strict requirements of the German data protection authorities when using Google Analytics.

**Demographic data collection by Google Analytics**

This website uses Google Analytics' demographic features. This allows reports to be generated containing  
statements about the age, gender, and interests of site visitors. This data comes from interest-based  
advertising from Google and third-party visitor data. This collected data cannot be attributed to any  
specific individual person. You can disable this feature at any time by adjusting the ads settings in your  
Google account or you can forbid the collection of your data by Google Analytics as described in the  
section "Refusal of data collection".

**Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking**  
This website uses Google AdWords. AdWords is an online advertising program from Google Inc., 1600  
Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ("Google").

As part of Google AdWords, we use so-called conversion tracking. When you click on an ad served by  
Google, a conversion tracking cookie is set. Cookies are small text files that your internet browser stores  
on your computer. These cookies expire after 30 days and are not used for personal identification of the  
user. Should the user visit certain pages of the website and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and  
the website can tell that the user clicked on the ad and proceeded to that page.

Each Google AdWords advertiser has a different cookie. Thus, cookies cannot be tracked using the  
website of an AdWords advertiser. The information obtained using the conversion cookie is used to create  
conversion statistics for the AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. Customers are  
told the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag  
page. However, advertisers do not obtain any information that can be used to personally identify users. If  
you do not want to participate in tracking, you can opt-out of this by easily disabling the Google  
Conversion Tracking cookie by changing your browser settings. In doing so, you will not be included in the  
conversion tracking statistics.

Conversion cookies are stored based on Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate  
interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

For more information about Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking, see the Google Privacy  
Policy: <https://www.google.de/policies/privacy/>

You can configure your browser to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a caseby-  
case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, your browser can be configured to  
automatically accept cookies under certain conditions or to always reject them, or to automatically delete  
cookies when closing your browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website.

###   
**6\. Newsletter**

**Newsletter data**  
If you would like to receive our newsletter, we require a valid email address as well as information that  
allows us to verify that you are the owner of the specified email address and that you agree to receive this  
newsletter. No additional data is collected or is only collected on a voluntary basis. We only use this data  
to send the requested information and do not pass it on to third parties.

We will, therefore, process any data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent per Art. 6 (1)  
(a) DSGVO. You can revoke consent to the storage of your data and email address as well as their use  
for sending the newsletter at any time, e.g. through the "unsubscribe" link in the newsletter. The data  
processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

The data provided when registering for the newsletter will be used to distribute the newsletter until you  
cancel your subscription when said data will be deleted. Data we have stored for other purposes (e.g.  
email addresses for the members area) remain unaffected.

###   
**7\. Plugins and tools**

**Google Web Fonts**  
For uniform representation of fonts, this page uses web fonts provided by Google. When you open a  
page, your browser loads the required web fonts into your browser cache to display texts and fonts  
correctly.

For this purpose your browser has to establish a direct connection to Google servers. Google thus  
becomes aware that our web page was accessed via your IP address. The use of Google Web fonts is  
done in the interest of a uniform and attractive presentation of our website. This constitutes a justified  
interest pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO.

If your browser does not support web fonts, a standard font is used by your computer.

Further information about handling user data, can be found at <https://developers.google.com/fonts/faq> and  
in Google's privacy policy at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

###   
**8\. Payment service providers**

**Paydirekt**  
Our website accepts payments via Paydirekt. The provider of this service is Paydirekt GmbH, Hamburger  
Allee 26-28, 60486 Frankfurt am Main, Germany (hereafter referred to as “Paydirekt”).

When you make payments through Paydirekt, Paydirekt collects various pieces of transaction data and  
forwards it to the bank you have indicated to Paydirekt. In addition to the data required for the payment,  
Paydirekt will also collect such data as your shipping address or the items in your shopping cart.

Paydirekt then authenticates the transaction by using the authentication method your bank has set up.  
The payment is then transferred from your account to ours. Neither we nor third parties have access to  
your account information.

For more information, see the terms and conditions and privacy policy of Paydirekt at  
<https://www.paydirekt.de/agb/index.html>

**Data Security:**  
Your personal information is safe with us! They are encrypted and transmitted to us through SSL128Bit.

Our websites are protected by technical measures against damage, destruction, unauthorized access.

**To provide information & Withdrawal:**  
They receive at any time without giving reasons for free information about your stored data.

You can always place your lock us in correcting the data collected, or deleted.

You can always granted us permission for data collection and use without giving any reason revoked.

Apply this to support@karatbars.com
